A Guide to the International Affairs Records: Study Abroad Brochures and University Council for International Programs, 1982-2007
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
International Education/Study Abroad Records, 1982-2007
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 35/1/2
1.4 cu. ft. 1 box
The International Education/Study Abroad Records include a collection of brochures relating to study abroad programs between 1982 and 2007 and minutes, notes, schedules, and strategic planning documents from the University Council for International Programs from 1995-2003.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Outreach and International Affairs.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Administrative History
The Committee on International Programs (1971-1972) later became the Office of International Development (OIRD). OIRD became the Office of International Research, Education, and Development (OIRED) on November 1, 2002. The portfolio was later enlarged, and as of 2014, it is Outreach and International Affairs, which includes both an engagement component and International Affairs, with associate vice presidents in charge of each. See the organizational chart as accessed on January 15, 2014.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series I: Study Abroad Brochures, 1982-2007. This series contains brochures published by the Office of International Programs advertising and outlining a variety of Virginia Tech faculty-led study abroad trips. The brochures document the courses, costs, itineraries, and general descriptions of each program. The contents are arranged chronologically with a separate folder for each year within the series.
Series II: University Council for International Programs, 1995-2003. This series contains documentation of minutes outlining the monthly meeting of the University Council for International Programs from 1995-2003. The first two years of the series (1995-1996) contain notes and minutes from each year arranged chronologically in the corresponding folders. The following years are separated into folders representing each month from September to April of each year. In addition to the minutes, some folders contain notes, attendance records, strategic planning documentation, and special reports issued by the Council.
Scope and Content
The International Education/Study Abroad Records include a collection of brochures relating to study abroad programs between 1982 and 2007 and minutes, notes, schedules, and strategic planning documents from the University Council for International Programs from 1995-2003. The records are arranged into two series: Series I: Study Abroad Brochures and Series II: University Council for International Programs.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Office of International Research, Education, and Development.; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Outreach and International Affairs.; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. University Outreach and International Affairs.
Subjects:
University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Series I: Study Abroad Brochures, 1982-2007
  - 1982 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - 1994 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Summer 1997 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Summer 1998 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Summer 1999 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Summer 2000 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - 2001 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - 2002 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - 2003 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Summer 2004 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Summer 2006 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - 2007 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Series II: University Council for International Programs, 1995-2003
  - Minutes, 1995-2003
    - 1995 (Box-folder 1-13)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 1-14)
    - September 1997 (Box-folder 1-15)
    - October 1997 (Box-folder 1-16)
    - November 1997 (Box-folder 1-17)
    - January 1998 (Box-folder 1-18)
    - February 1998 (Box-folder 1-19)
    - March 1998 (Box-folder 1-20)
    - April 1998 (Box-folder 1-21)
    - May 1998 (Box-folder 1-22)
    - September 1998 (Box-folder 1-25)
    - October 1998 (Box-folder 1-26)
    - November 1998 (Box-folder 1-27)
    - December 1998 (Box-folder 1-28)
    - January 1999 (Box-folder 1-29)
    - February 1999 (Box-folder 1-30)
    - March 1999 (Box-folder 1-31)
    - April 1999 (Box-folder 1-32)
    - May 1999 (Box-folder 1-33)
    - September 1999 (Box-folder 1-34)
    - October 1999 (Box-folder 1-35)
    - November 1999 (Box-folder 1-36)
    - January 2000 (Box-folder 1-37)
    - February 2000 (Box-folder 1-38)
    - April 2000 (Box-folder 1-39)
    - May 2000 (Box-folder 1-40)
    - October 2000 (Box-folder 1-45)
    - January 2001 (Box-folder 1-46)
    - February 2001 (Box-folder 1-47)
    - March 2001 (Box-folder 1-48)
    - April 2001 (Box-folder 1-49)
    - May 2001 (Box-folder 1-50)
    - September 2001 (Box-folder 1-52)
    - October 2001 (Box-folder 1-53)
    - November 2001 (Box-folder 1-54)
    - December 2001 (Box-folder 1-55)
    - January 2002 (Box-folder 1-56)
    - March 2002 (Box-folder 1-57)
    - April 2002 (Box-folder 1-58)
    - September 2002 (Box-folder 1-60)
    - October 2002 (Box-folder 1-61)
    - November 2002 (Box-folder 1-62)
    - December 2002 (Box-folder 1-63)
    - January 2003 (Box-folder 1-64)
    - February 2003 (Box-folder 1-65)
    - March 2003 (Box-folder 1-66)
    - April 2003 (Box-folder 1-67)
    - Electronic minutes, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 1-69)
  - Linkage Agreement and General Information, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Members, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 1-24)
  - Strategic Directions 3.5, 1999 (Box-folder 1-41)
  - Global Focus Group, 2000 (Box-folder 1-42)
  - Strategic Planning, 2000 (Box-folder 1-43)
  - Notes, Functions, 2000 (Box-folder 1-44)
  - Undergraduate and Graduate Reps, 2000 (Box-folder 1-51)
  - Notes and Schedules, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 1-59)
  - Notes and Schedules, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 1-68)